I'm counting on you!
（あおい）
よろしくお願いします
（橋本(はしもと)）
う～ん 俺 ここの
つり橋 逃げるシーン引き取るよ
I'll take this part, where they escape on the rope bridge.
But that scene looks really difficult to do.
（内田(うちだ)）
え～ 大変なところなのに？
I want to give it a shot anyway.
I mean, it's the finale.
いや ちょっとやってみたい
最終話だし
Then I'll do the section before that,
where Alpine's running with a fursuit on.
（内田）
じゃあ 私 その前の
着ぐるみあるぴんが走るとこ
やろうかな
Miyamori-san, how many more cuts are in episode 13?
（清野）
宮森(みやもり)さん 13話 あと何カット？
Let's see...
（あおい）
えっと 30です
About thirty.
When will Iguchi-san be done with episode 12?
井口(いぐち)さんが12話終わるのって
いつだっけ？
By the end of today!
（井口）今日だよ～
（一同）うん？
Then I'm getting right on 13.
（井口）
上がったら13話やるよ～
Yasuharacchi, got a spare minute?
安原(やすはら)っちは手空いてないの？
（絵麻(えま)）
えっ あっ 今… 13話の
Ａパートのほう まだやってて…
I'm still working on part A for episode 13.
Layouts are scheduled for tomorrow, right?
（あおい）
あしたレイアウトアップだっけ？
（絵麻）うん
（あおい）終わりそう？
Will you be done?
I think so.
（絵麻）なんとか…
（井口）あそこのさ
You should do that scene,
the one where the three run down the stairs.
３人が階段 駆け下りるシーン
描きなよ
あっ いいんですか？
結構 大事なシーン…
May I? It's such an important one.
That's exactly why you should do it.
大事なシーンだからやるんだよ
Yeah, you'll be fine! You've got a real knack for getting girls' delicate movements right.
（橋本）
いいんじゃない　安原さん
女の子のやわらかい動き
うまいな～と思ってたんだ
He's right!
（内田）だよね！
（絵麻）ハッ おいちゃん…
Oi-chan?
うん やってくれると助かる
It'd be a huge help if you did it!
I suppose...
じゃあ…
Great, only twenty-seven cuts to go!
残り27カットです
What about Sugie-san?
（絵麻）
杉江(すぎえ)さんは？
No way. That'd kill the ADs.
（清野）
無理でしょ　作監 死んじゃうよ
A few decades ago, he might've been able to wing it, but these days...
（内田）
30年前ならともかく
今の絵は無理なんじゃ…
I doubt he'd want to do it anyway.
（橋本）
描く気もないだろうしな
I'll try asking people outside of the studio too.
社外の人にも
頼んでみようと思います
Thanks. Go get 'em, production!
おう 頑張れ制作
Now the question is...
…とは言ったものの
Who's going to do the horses?
（内田）
あの馬のシーン
どうするんだろう？
The Little Keyframe Girl
Good afternoon! This is Miyamori Aoi
from Musashino Animation.
あっ お世話になっております
武蔵野(むさしの)アニメーションの
宮森あおいと申します
Do you have a minute to talk?
あっ はい
今 お電話 大丈夫でしょうか？
Oh, great!
ありがとうございます
To be honest, I'm actually calling with a request.
実は非常に ぶしつけな
お願いなんですが
Could you introduce me
佐々木(ささき)さんのお知り合いで
「えくそだすっ！」最終話の原画を
to any of your acquaintances who might be willing to do keyframes for Exodus's finale?
手伝っていただけそうな方を
ご存じないでしょうか？
No one's really coming to mind.
（佐々木）
ごめんなさい
ちょっと見当がつかなくて
I wish I could help you. Sorry.
誰か紹介できるといいんですけど
すみません
No, if anything I should be sorry,
calling you out of nowhere and asking for help.
あっ いえ こちらこそ
いきなりのお願いで
申し訳ありませんでした
Let's stay in touch! Bye!
また よろしくお願いします
失礼します
We're doing the final rush of the coming winter season anime.
（木佐(きさ)）
今 ちょうど１月新番の
追い込みだからな～
Keep  it up!
I'll ask around, but I can't make any promises.
聞いてみるけど
期待しないでくれる？
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Me?
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
俺？　今は無理
退院したら超頑張るから
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Not a chance. But I plan on working my ass off once I'm out of hospital.
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
Keep  it up!
Stupid!
Hurt
Get well quick!
Cheer up!
I asked around, but I couldn't get anyone.
（瀬川(せがわ)）
ちょっと聞いてみたんだけど
みんな無理っぽい　ごめんね
I'm sorry.
It's fine. I understand it's a busy time of year.
（あおい）
そうですよね
時期が時期ですもんね
Regardless, I'm going to keep at it and get the help we need!
でも！　頑張って いっぱい
声かけてみようと思います！
I'm counting on you as the AD for part A!
引き続き Ａパートの作監
よろしくお願いします
Yes, of course.
それは はい
Hello?
あっ もしもし
突然で申し訳ないのですが
Sorry for such a sudden call,
but I'd like to ask if you could do
keyframes for Exodus, Mitani-san.
「えくそだすっ！」の原画をですね
ぜひ三谷(みたに)さんに…
That's right. The director is Kinoshita—
あっ はい そうです
木下(きのした)監督の…
Not a chance.
（三谷）
それ無理だから
Ah, Mitani-san from Zone?
I'm not surprised he refused.
（矢野(やの)）
あ～ ゾーンの三谷さんなら
断るかもね
He probably still has nightmares from BoingPara.
昔 「ぷる天」で
痛い目 見たからじゃない？
Nightmares?
痛い目？
He was the AD, but the director's
storyboards set the entire schedule back.
作監だったのに
監督の絵コンテ作業で
スケジュール食いつぶされて
That resulted in a bunch of shoddy work getting released under his name.
何もできずに
クオリティーきつい話数―
名前だけ出ちゃったって話
Oh, I see.
あ～ それは…
But there are only twenty cuts left.
でも あと20カットなんですけど
う～ん 重いのばっかり
残ってるからな
And they're all hard ones.
Well, look on the bright side.
（矢野）
ピンチはチャンスだと
思うしかないよね
This'll be a good chance for you to meet new people. Good luck!
人脈を広げる
いいチャンスだと思って頑張ろう
Sure! So do you know anyone that could do it?
頑張ります！　なので矢野さんの
知り合いを紹介してください
I gave you a few names the other day!
この間 教えたじゃん
あれで全部だよ
That's already everyone.
But there's gotta be—
（あおい）
でも どこかに まだ誰か…
You know, there are a lot of people who claim to be keyframe animators.
あのね 自称原画マンって
レベルの人なら
そりゃ いないでもないよ
But if they're not up to it,
you know who's gonna be hurting?
でも そういう人にオファー出して
困るのは誰だ？
The episode director, keyframe AD,
chief AD, director...
演出と作監 総作監 監督…
（矢野）違う 自分だ
（あおい）うっ
No! It's you!
Me?
自分… ですか？
Hire just anyone to get it wrapped up ASAP,
作打ちを
早く終わらせたいばっかりに
and the cuts will end up stalled at the ED and the AD checks.
内容的に微妙な人たちを入れたら
それは必ず演出と
作監チェックで止まる
Characters will look weird, the composition even weirder, and movements all janky.
キャラが似てなかったり
構図が変だったり
動きが足りなかったりと
You'd have to get a lot fixed.
直さなきゃならないことが
たくさんあるからね
Or even worse, redo the whole thing from scratch.
下手すれば１から
全直しなんてこともありえる
Not only would you be short on time and causing trouble for the ED and AD,
だから結局 演出と作監に
迷惑かけた上に
たたでさえないスケジュールが
押しまくって
but you'd have to run around like a
headless chicken, trying to get retakes done.
土壇場のリテーク対応でヒーヒー
走り回るのは自分だってこと
Keep that in mind.
ちゃんと覚えとく
I will!
はい！
Keyframers? I'd love to find some too!
（落合(おちあい)）
原画マン？
そんなもん こっちが欲しいわ！
It's not easy, but we're having fun.
まあ ピンチはピンチで
楽しいけどな
There's no way I could keep this up if it weren't.
つか 楽しいと思わないと
やってけないけどな
はあ～ 落合さんにも
無理って言われました
Ochiai-san couldn't get me anyone, either.
Man, this manga is awesome.
（太郎(たろう)）
この漫画
マジいけるんじゃないっすかね
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing.
「第三飛行少女隊」
I wonder if we'll ever get a project like this.
こういう企画
誰か持ってこねえかな～
No way we'd land a franchise that popular.
（本田(ほんだ)）
そんな人気作 うちにはこないよ
The big studios are on it already, I bet.
もっと大手がとっくに
唾つけてるよ
Way to rain on my parade.
うわ～ しょっぺえっすな～
Tarou, don't forget that Exodus isn't over yet.
太郎 お前 一人
終わった気になってんじゃないぞ
Episode 12 is already dubbed, so as far as
I'm concerned, I'm pretty much good to go here.
まっ 私の12話は
既にダビングも終了
ここまできたら
完成したも同然ですからね
Wait, weren't there still plenty of retakes to be done?
…ってリテークかなり残ってるよね
（内線の着信音）
This is Takanashi Tarou at your service.
はい こちら皆さまの
高梨(たかなし)太郎でございます
え！　はっ はい！
ごめんなさい 忘れてました！
Sorry! I totally forgot about it! I'll bring it up right away!
すぐ上に持っていきます！
（本田）あっ…
（矢野）ホント成長しないな
He never learns, does he?
"If I fell asleep, would I wake to find that dwarves had done all the keyframes?"
（ミムジー）
目が覚めたら小人さんが
全部原画を描いといてくれないかな
Is that what you're thinking?
…なんて考えてる？
No! I swear, I'm not!
（ロロ）
うっ 思ってないよ
思ってないってば
If you still have time for dumb
wishful thinking, put it to better use!
まだ余裕だね
夢 見る暇があるんだから
I'm just trying to escape reality a little.
違うよ
ちょっとした現実逃避だよ
You can't weave dreams while you're busy daydreaming.
夢みたいなお話を作るには
夢だけ見てちゃ作れないのさ
Realists are so harsh.
うわ～ つらいよ せちがらいよ
I see!
（あおい）
あっ そうですか
Onodera-san moved to The Born?
小野寺(おのでら)さんはザ･ボーンに
移られたんですね
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます
Onodera-san's always been a night owl.
He should be coming soon.
小野寺さん 夜型だったから
そろそろスタジオ入りするはず
Then when he shows up...
その瞬間を狙ってガオ～！
You're such a man-eater.
（ロロ）
肉食女子だ～
That's not it!
そういう意味じゃないよ
I've gotta go the whole nine yards to even have a chance of catching him!
こうでもしないと
捕まえられないんだから―
しかたないでしょ
（車の走行音）
Ah, someone's coming.
（ロロ）あっ 誰か来た
（ミムジー）あっ
The Born
Job Interview
Hitotsubashi, huh?
（伊波(いなみ)）
一橋(ひとつばし)か
You're the first I've met today who's come from there.
うちに応募来たの初めてだな
（応募者）
恐縮です
It's an honor.
Why anime then? Why not pursue economics?
Inami Masahiko
The Born    President
なんでアニメなの？
経済やってればいいんじゃないの？
Anime is one of the few products of Japan that has global demand and appeal.
（応募者）
アニメというものは
日本が世界に誇れる―
産業の一つだと思います
I especially believe in the potential of this studio and the style of your works.
私は中でも御社のポテンシャルと
作品の方向性に注目しております
（伊波）
ふ～ん 宮森さんは？　志望動機
What about you, Miyamori-san?
Why did you apply here?
はい？　あっ はい わらしゃ
あの えっと…
Ah, yes.
I, uh... Um...
Am I scaring you?
Takekura Keiji
The Born    Production Chief
俺 そんな怖い？
Your words hit hard, boss.
（竹倉(たけくら)）
社長は
威圧感あるんですよ
Really?
（伊波）そうかな
（あおい）すみません
I'm sorry.
はあ～ 高校時代
部活動でアニメを作って
I made an anime in high school with my friends.
I just couldn't forget how fun it was.
その楽しさが
忘れられなかったからです
In high school? That's unusual.
高校で　へえ～ 珍しいね
でも短大は経済学部？
But you graduated in economics, right?
I wasn't confident... Rather, I couldn't make up my mind after high school.
進学時は自信がなかったというか
覚悟ができませんでした
それで…
So you got a degree just in case?
（伊波）
とりあえず行ったってことか
あっ はい
Yes.
でっ 今回 改めて業界に
入りたいと思ったと
And now you've decided that it's time to start working in the industry?
Think you can handle it?
やってく自信はあるの？
Yes! I'll do anything! Give me a chance!
あります！　なんでもやります
やらせてください！
はあ～ なんでもやるって言葉
俺 嫌いなんだよね
I hate people who will do anything.
It means you've got nothing you specifically want to do.
（伊波）
それってつまり
やりたいことがないってことだよね
Look, there you go being mean again.
ほら また威圧する
Could you try being nice to the young'uns?
若人に優しさがないですよ
Come on, I'm nice.
いやいや 俺は優しいよ
優しいよね？
I am, right?
Sorry...
（あおい）
すみません…
You should probably think some more on it, Miyamori-san.
まっ もう一回よく考えたほうが
いいと思うよ　宮森さん
Notice
The Born Inc.
Ms. Miyamori,
Thank you
very much for
applying for a productio
n staff position.
Sadly, how
ever, after car
eful consideration,
we conclu
ded that we
cannot hire you at this time.
We wish y
ou good luck
with finding a job.
Sincerely,
As for the staff recruitment, after
careful inspection of your application,
we are sad to inform you that we c
annot hire you at this time. We are
very sorry, but ask for your kind un
derstanding.
We wish you good luck in the
future
Regards,
Japan Animation Inc.
Thank you very much for ta
king our recruitment exam.
We carefully evaluated the t
ests, and sadly your application did not pass.
We are very sorry that we c
an not hire you at this time
and ask for your kind under
stand in the matter.
We wish you good luck in
the future.
Look at all those good luck wishes!
（かおり）
うわ～ いっぱい お祈りされてる
Sis...
ねいちゃん
Seems like your future is pretty much hopeless.
（かおり）
これが前途に希望が持てない
若人の姿だよ
（あおい）うっ…
（かおり）見てごらん
I think her heart's almost broken too!
心が折れそうになってるよ
No, it's not!
折れてないもん
There are plenty more anime companies! Just look them up online!
アニメの会社なんて
いくらでもあるでしょ
ネットあされ ネット
You can't park your car here.
It's in the way. Can you move?
ここに止められると邪魔なんで
移動してもらえる？
Musani?
ムサニ？
はいっ すみません！
すぐ どかします
Right! Sorry!
I'll get out of the way right now!
（エンジン音）
（伊波）いや ゆっくりでいいから
Take it easy.
Don't want no accidents.
事故ったらマズいし
O-Of course! That's for sure!
はっ はい そうだすよね！
Do I know you?
どっかで会ったっけ？
Oh, never mind. Take care.
（伊波）
まあ いいや　移動よろしく
You too! Thank you!
はい お疲れさまです
（クラクション）
Who was that again?
誰だっけな～
Onodera-san!
（あおい）小野寺さん
（小野寺）うん？
Whoa, you surprised me.
うわっ ビックリした！
あれ？　えっと… ムサニの
You're from Musani, right?
I'm Miyamori.
宮森です
I'd like to ask you to do keyframes.
実は小野寺さんに
原画のお願いがありまして
Sorry, I don't do keyframes anymore.
ごめん
俺もう原画やってないんだよ
Lately, I've been directing instead.
演出一本でいこうって決めて
Well, I thought I'd try it out, and it was perfect for me.
（小野寺）
やってみたら演出が
肌に合ってるっつうか
If you ever need a director, please give me a call.
そっちの仕事あったら声かけてよ
やるよ
I'll be happy to do it!
Sure, but...
あっ はい　でも…
Musani's getting accolades for making a nice comeback.
（小野寺）
ムサニ盛り返してきたねって
評判だよ
Exodus is the big sleeper hit of this season.
「えくそだすっ！」今期のビックリ
ダークホース枠だったよ
R-Right... Thank you.
（あおい）
あっ はい　ありがとうございます
I'm under contract until the end of the year.
（原画マン１）
年内まで作品契約でさ
I can't take any other jobs on top of that.
他の仕事と
掛け持ちできないんだよね
Damn, if only you had come a little earlier.
（原画マン２）
あ～ 一足遅かったよ
ゾーンの仕事 昨日受けたとこ
I took some work from Zone just yesterday.
Whoa, these cuts all look pretty difficult.
（原画マン３）
え～ むっちゃヘビーなカット
ばっかじゃん
I couldn't do it on this schedule.
このスケジュールじゃ無理だよ
I've got some doujin manga to draw right now.
If it can wait, I can do three cuts or so when I'm done.
（ｲﾝﾀｰﾌｫﾝ:原画マン４）
同人誌の原稿があるんで
その後でよければ
３カットくらいはできるかな
Thank you very much!
（あおい）
ありがとうございます！
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Murai-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Muroi-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Mori-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Murai-san, Yuri-san, and Yota-san can't do it.
（あおい）
村井(むらい)さんアウト ユリさんアウト
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Muroi-san
Mori-san
Murakami-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Muroi-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Muroi-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Yota-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Mori-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Group        Animators
Matsuoka-san
Murai-san
Murakami-san
Muroi-san
Muguro Yuri-san
Mori-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
依田(よだ)さんアウト
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Wakana Kenichi-san
Group        Animators
Yota-san
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Wakana Kenichi-san
Group        Animators
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Wakana Kenichi-san
Wada Tomomi-san
Group        Animators
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Wakana Kenichi-san
Wada Tomomi-san
Group        Animators
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Wakana Kenichi-san
Wada Tomomi-san
Group        Animators
Tatsuzaki-san
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Wakana Kenichi-san
Wada Tomomi-san
Watanabe-san
Group        Animators
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Wakana Kenichi-san
Wada Tomomi-san
Watanabe-san
Group        Animators
Ryou-san
Reika-san
Wakana Kenichi-san
Wada Tomomi-san
Watanabe-san
I'm running out of people to ask.
後はもう ラ行とワ行の人しか…
それでもダメだったら
どうすればいいかな
What will I do if they all refuse?
う～ん うっ　すみません
Sorry...
Good morning!
（就活生たち）
おはようございます
あっ おはようございます
G-Good morning!
Today, after the morning meeting,
（興津(おきつ)）
本日 朝礼が終了次第
第一会議室で
制作の採用面接を行います
we will be interviewing potential recruits for production staff.
面接は社長がメインで行いますが
宮森さんもお願いします
The president will lead the interviews. Miyamori-san, you're to join him.
高梨君は運転実技のほうを
担当してください
Takanashi-kun, you will be
evaluating their driving skills.
Me? Doing the interviews?
（あおい）
私が面接？　するんですか！
Wait, interviews?!
I will be there too.
（興津）
私もやります
I'm counting on you, Miyamori-kun, Takanashi-kun.
（丸川(まるかわ)）
よろしくね 宮森君 高梨君
Just leave it to me!
任せてくださいよ！
I'm fairly confident in my ability to judge people!
人を見る目にはちょっと
かなり自信ありますよ
絶対 顔で選ぶなよ
Don't you dare judge them by their looks.
Hey, I'd do nothing of the sort!
僕がそんな不純な目で
選ぶと思いますか！
Though we don't need more
suave guys. That'd be trouble.
あっ でもイケメンはやだな
やりにくいよな
ホントに私でいいんですか？
渡辺(わたなべ)さんとか
Am I really qualified for this?
Shouldn't Watanabe-san do it?
I'm terrible at judging people.
（渡辺）
俺 人を見る目ないんで
Then Yano-san! Yano-san could!
矢野さん！　矢野さんとか
（丸川）
興津君と矢野君が宮森君を
推薦したんだよ
Okitsu-kun and Yano-kun recommended you.
I'm counting on you.
よろしくお願いします
But how should I evaluate people?
でも 人を評価するようなこと…
You'll be working with whoever we choose,
so you should get to know them now.
これから ともに
働く人を見つけるんだから
宮森君にも参加してほしいな
別に 人に優劣を
つけるわけじゃない
You don't have to score them or anything like that.
Just see if you might work well together.
一緒に いい仕事が
できるかどうかだよ
Together...
一緒に…
（本田）
…って就活本の受け売りだけど
This is what job hunting looks like from the other side.
I hope you can find some nice people.
まっ いい人が見つかるよう
祈ってるよ
な～んて辞めてく
俺が言うのも あれだけど
Probably sounds weird from me, seeing as I'm about to quit!
（就活生１）
よろしくお願いします
Good morning!
Thanks for coming in for the interview.
面接に来てくれてありがとうね～
でも なんでうちなの？
What made you choose us?
（就活生１）
あっ はい わたくしは子供の頃から
アニメが大好きで
I've loved anime ever since I was a kid.
I especially loved your work, Heidi, Girl of Oedo!
特に御社の「大江戸少女ヘイジ」が
大好きで
I thought I'd love to work on a project like that!
このような作品を
作ってみたいと思いました
But Heidi was done by Souei, not us.
（興津）
「ヘイジ」はうちじゃなくて
ソーエイの作品ですが
（就活生１）
え～！　だあ～！
（丸川）
アハハ 会社はともかく
Regardless of who made it,
what did you like about Heidi?
ヘイジの
どういうところが好きなの？
（就活生１）
え～ その…
How cheerful Heidi was and how well her father's character was designed.
ヘイジの明るいところや
親分もキャラが立ってて
いやいや立っており
And the final scene with Frankfurt was really powerful!
ラストのフランクフルトの
出入りシーンが
The way Heidi smacked Mark—
すごく迫力があって
ヘイジの殴るマルクが…
Y'know, just... Thing is...
（就活生２）
え～と なんつかさ～
なんとなくっつうか
I gathered massive amounts of data from the Internet and analyzed it.
（就活生３）
わたくしのネットによる―
膨大な情報を
かき集めて分析した結果
I found that viral marketing is getting
overshadowed by catastrophe marketing and—
ネットでは 既に
もう炎上マーケティングの
その上をいく
カタストロフマーケティング…
（佐藤(さとう)）
アニメはギブリぐらいで
あまり見たことがありません
I am familiar with Gibri anime, but nothing else really.
I worked in a shopping mall in Makuhari as a secretary and in customer service for three years.
仕事は幕張(まくはり)の
ショッピングモールで
接客と事務を３年経験しました
（丸川）
ほお～ なんでうちに？
Why did you apply here?
はい　私は今 通勤に
３時間かかっているのですが
It takes me three hours to
commute to my current job.
この時間を もっと有効に
使えないかと思いまして
I considered ways to utilize that time more efficiently.
自宅の近くで御社の
募集があることを知り
When I found out that you were recruiting and so close to my home, my mind was made up.
これだと すぐに決意しました
（丸川）
この業界 なかなか大変だよ？
It's not an easy job, you know.
I'm aware. I looked up the details.
大丈夫です
いろいろ調べましたから
I'm confident in my stamina!
（安藤(あんどう)）
体力には自信があります
I've worked part-time in
convenience stores since high school!
高校時代から
コンビニでバイトしてました
I've got an expensive hobby,
so I have to make money to support it!
お金のかかる趣味をしてたんで
その分 稼ぎたくて
（丸川）
お金のかかる趣味って？
What is your expensive hobby?
ヘッ アニメの同人誌です
Creating anime doujins!
I've released about thirty so far.
これまでに30種類は
出したと思います
You really like anime, don't you?
（丸川）
アニメ好きなんだね
Yes! I love anime, but to be completely honest,
はい！　好きなんですけど
客観的に見て
I can't draw well enough to become an animator.
アニメーターになれる画力が
あるとは思っていません
だったら何が
できるだろうと考えて
I thought about other ways I could contribute,
自分がやるなら調整役とか
進行役だろうと
and that's in management or production jobs.
Hey.
おっつ
あっ お疲れさまです
（お湯を注ぐ音）
Hello.
Any good applicants?
（矢野）
よさげな人いた？
みんな 有能っぽいし
いい人に見えるんですけど
They all seem capable and nice and all that...
That can't be right. We even had to hire Tarou...
うちは太郎ですら
採用しちゃうんだから
なんで私が面接官なんですか？
Why am I helping with the interviews, anyway?
You'd be much better at this.
矢野さんのほうが
絶対 向いてるのに
う～ん
そんなにプレッシャー？
Is it that tough?
I just...
（あおい）なんかもう…
（矢野）うん？
It reminds me of when I was in their shoes. It's depressing.
（あおい）
自分が面接 受けた時のこと
思い出してヘコみます
Huh? Why?
へ？　なんで？
Did you apply to other production companies too?
（丸川）
他にも どこか制作会社 受けた？
あっ はい
採用していただけませんでしたが
Yes, but they didn't hire me.
I see. Have you thought about why that is?
（丸川）
おお そっか…
なんでか考えてみた？
受けたところがG.I.STAFFとか
サンアップとかザ･ボーンとか
I applied to companies like
G.I. Staff, Sunup, and The Born.
レベルが高いところ
ばかりだったので
All of them are top anime studios.
（丸川）
それでムサニにしたんだね
So you thought Musani might be different?
I didn't mean to say Musani's not any good—
えっ あっ そのムサニが
レベル低いとかじゃなく
御社が自分に合った
レベルじゃなくて… あ～
just maybe more appropriate for me—
I mean...
I know what that's like.
あるある 若さゆえの過ち
みんな そんなもんだよ
Being young and foolish.
We've all been there.
Really?
（あおい）ですかね～
（矢野）そう
Yeah. People say it's all about "trial and error,"
トライ＆エラーって言うけど
but it's more like "trial and trouble."
日々トライ＆トラブル
なんてね
Never mind me.
I might be Iron Yano, but I'm kind of pooped.
さすがのアイアン矢野も
お疲れ中
Sorry I'm such a mess.
（あおい）すみません 頼りなくて
（携帯電話のバイブ音）
Aunt Mennouchi
Incoming
エリカだけど
It's Erika.
うん　え？　そう…
Huh? I see.
（太郎）
言っとくけど
Let me tell you something!
Looks mean nothing to me.
俺は顔では選ばないからね
You're too young to know this,
but all that matters is the mood you set!
若いと まだ分かんないだろうけど
まず大事なのは雰囲気ね
ふいんきじゃないよ　ふ･ん…
Not just any mood. The mo—
気が散るんで黙っててください！
Please stop! I'm trying to concentrate here!
はい
Okay.
Whoever gets hired, they can't possibly be worse than Tarou.
（円(まどか)）
どんなヤツが来ようと
太郎よりマシでしょ
（山田(やまだ)）
あ～ そういう考え方があったか
Yeah, I guess that's one way to think about it.
ある意味
ポジティブシンキング
Looking at the bright side, I see.
（円）
とはいえ 次の作品 決まってから
Wouldn't it be better to hire someone after our next project is set in stone, though?
募集かけるんでもよかったと
思いますけどね～
（木下(きのした)）
企画が決まる時は一瞬で決まる
Once projects are confirmed, work starts right away.
それから慌てても遅いんだよ
Then it'd be too late to find someone.
Are we even getting a new project?
（円）
そもそも決まるんですか？
ナベＰが
動いてんじゃないの？
NabeP's up to something, anyhow.
Really? I still can't figure him out, to be honest.
（円）
あの人もな～
イマイチ読めないからな
いやいや ヤツは優秀だよ
Don't worry, he's a talented guy.
（葛城(かつらぎ)）ナベちゃ～ん
（渡辺）うっす
Nabe-chan!
Hey.
ちょっと ちょっと　ナベちゃん
今日この後 暇？
Listen now, Nabe-chan!
Got any plans for after this?
忙しいわけないじゃないっすか
Nope, my day's free.
じゃあ天牌(てんぱい) 行こうよ
Let's go to Tenpai then!
夜鷹(よたか)書房の
尾之上(おのうえ)さんも来るから
Onoue-san from Nighthawk Publishing
will be there too.
う～わ 尾之上さん強いからな
Ugh, he's a tough cookie.
I better get ready to lose.
またボコボコにされるんですかね
That's not it. I want to settle it today.
違う 違う
今日は決めたいんだよ
Sorry, I really can't take any more right now.
（原画マン）
ごめんよ～ でも もうホントに
いっぱい いっぱいで
あっ いえ
また ご連絡させていただきます
It's okay. But we should stay in touch, just in case.
ありがとうございま～す
Thank you anyway!
（原画マン）ほ～い
（あおい）失礼いたします
Sure.
Goodbye!
Keyframes? Keyframes anyone?
（あおい）
原画は… 原画の仕事は
いりませんか？
今なら引き受け放題
You can do as many as you'd like!
They're really cheap, too!
お安くしておきま～す
No one will do them if you say that.
安いんじゃ
誰もやってくれないよ
Someone... Do keyframes for me please...
誰か… 誰か原画を…
Someone...
誰か… うっ うっ あっ
This is the house of Bee Production!
ここは
ビープロダクションのおうちだわ
さっすが町で一番の人気工房
人もいっぱいいるね
That's the most popular studio in town for you.
Look at all the people there.
Amazing...
すごいや あんなに残っていた
カットが次々に上がっていく
There are so many cuts, but they all get done one after another.
（あおい）
ここはサンアップ
And this is Sunup!
（ミムジー）
ロボットが手描きなのに
バリバリ動いてるよ
The robots are all hand drawn, but look how they move!
（ロロ）
ロボットアニメはサンアップだって
言われるだけあるよね
Sunup's known as the robot anime studio for a reason.
（杉江）
お先に
See you tomorrow.
What's wrong, Yano-san?
（太郎）
どうしたんすか？　矢野さん
（木下）
やけどは？
やけど してないか？　お湯
Did you burn yourself? Are you all right?
えっ… あっ はい
Y-Yeah...
矢野君
お父さんのことかい？
Yano-kun, is it about your father?
はあ～ 今11時過ぎか
電車じゃ無理だな
It's already past 11.
The trains aren't running anymore.
何言ってんすか？　社長
What are you talking about, President?
（丸川）
あっ 矢野君のお父さまがね
今 入院なさってて
Yano-kun's father is in hospital.
It's okay.
大丈夫です
My aunt is with him.
叔母が一緒にいてくれますから
ダメだよ 帰りなさい
No, it's not okay.
You should go to them.
とはいっても 矢野さん
宇都宮(うつのみや)だったよね
But you're from Utsunomiya, right?
はあ～ あしたの始発を待つより
Going by car would be faster than waiting for the first train tomorrow.
車で行ったほうが早いね～
本田君
Honda-kun, would you?
Miyamori's using car 1, but you can take car 2.
１号車は宮森さんが
使ってるけど
２号車があるから
それ使って
いやいや… 今の矢野に
運転させるのかよ
Hold on a moment. You can't possibly tell her to drive in that state.
（本田）ああ…
（太郎）てことは…
Does that mean...
It's time for Musani's
secret weapon to take the wheel!
いよいよ出ますか！
ムサニのリーサルウェポンが！
The ace driver's in the hot seat for this tough situation,
この重大局面に
エースドライバー投入
and it's no stretch to claim that it is I who carries Musani on his shoulders!
もはやムサニの中核を
担うといっても過言ではない！
（一同）
過言だろ！
Yes it is.
いいから行って
Just get going already.
Tank full!
（エンジン音）
（太郎）ガソリンよ～し
Seat belts fastened!
シートベルトよ～し
ライトよ～し
Lights on!
Just settle down and try not to get in an accident.
（円）
テンション上げすぎて事故るなよ
（矢野）
すみません 本田さん
Sorry for the trouble, Honda-san.
仕事は心配ないから
Don't worry about your work now.
（丸川）
これ車の中で食べなさい
Eat this on the way.
ハムと卵のサンドイッチ
それと紅茶
Ham and egg sandwiches and some tea.
Drive safe.
安全運転でね
Tarou Takanashi. Go!
（太郎）
太郎高梨　ゴー！
（木下）
矢野ってさ
父一人 子一人なんだよな
Yano's father is her only family, right?
（山田）
え？　なんですか その小津(おづ)設定
Is this the Wizard of Oz now?
Oh no...
そうか
そうなんだよ
Right?
（あおい）
え！　高梨さんで
大丈夫なんですか？
Is it okay to send Takanashi-san?
Better than making Yano-san drive herself.
（本田）
う～ん 矢野さん自身よりは…
ただ矢野さんのヘルプが
消えたとなると
But with her gone, you're on your own with episode 13.
13話は かなりシビアな…
And I'm out of ideas.
万策尽きる寸前みたいな…
（あおい）ちょっと待ってください
（本田）え？
Wait a moment!
There's one person I haven't asked yet!
もう一人だけ
あたってない人がいました
Mahjong
Tenpai
Cancel
To    :  Honda PM
Sub  :  Re :
Roger.
---Original Message---
We sent
Yano-san home.
Her father's condition
Yeah, got it.
了解っと…
（携帯電話のバイブ音）
（渡辺）うん？　はい
Yes?
え？　何？
うん しばらくいるけど
Yeah. Why?
I'll be here for a while.
Huh?! Now?!
え！　今から？
Sakurada Nobuhiro
Dainippon Advertising    Producer
（尾之上）
おいおい 誰と話してんの？
ナベちゃん
Who are you talking to, Nabe-chan?
Hold on! I'm busy!
（渡辺）
ちょっ ちょ… 待て！
今 俺…
Ron!
（桜田）ロン！
（渡辺）ちょっ！　あ～！
Wai—
I'm Miyamori from Musashino Animation.
（あおい）
武蔵野アニメーションの
宮森と申します
Is Watanabe from our studio here?
弊社 渡辺は
こちらにいますでしょうか？
ちょ～い！　取り込み中だぞ
Hey! We're busy!
Thank goodness.
はあ～ よかった
よかったってなんだよ！
For what?!
I need you to introduce me to animators.
渡辺さんにアニメーターさんを
紹介してもらおうと思いまして
You worked as a PA and PM too before, right?
渡辺さん 昔は進行もデスクも
やってましたよね？
でしたら
お知り合いがいますよね？
Then you must know a lot of people!
はっ お知り合いって
Well, I—
（尾之上）
紹介してやんなよ
Introduce some people to her.
尾之上さん
Onoue-san?!
You're looking for animators?
Onoue Masato
Nighthawk Publishing    Editor-in-Chief
アニメーター探してるの？
はい！
That's right!
Want me to introduce you to some?
（尾之上）
僕が紹介してあげようか？
（あおい）お願いします！
（渡辺）尾之上さん
I would be very grateful!
Onoue-san!
菅野(かんの)とか知ってるかな？
Do you know Kanno?
Kanno...
菅野…
（尾之上）
菅野光明(みつあき)
Kanno Mitsuaki. The director of Neon Locomotive Evangardon.
「新世代アヴァンギャルドン」の
監督の
Come on, don't tease the newbie!
うちの若いの
からかうのは やめてください
え～ いいな～
That'd be fabulous! I'd love to get introduced to Kanno-san too!
俺だって菅野さんだったら
紹介してほしいですよ
Me too! But does he still draw?
ですよね～
でも まだアニメーター
やってるんですか？
（葛城）
現役ですよ ブ～ン
He sure does!
That would be a great help! Please do introduce me!
（あおい）ありがたいです！
（尾之上）え？
ぜひ よろしくお願いします！
（あおい）
ありがとうございました
失礼します
Thank you very much! Excuse me!
You're such a tease, Onoue-san.
尾之上さんも人が悪い
う～ん ホントに
菅野のとこ行ったと思う？
Do you think she's really going to see Kanno now?
I'm sure she is.
（桜田）思いますね
（葛城）思います
No doubt about it.
間違いなく行きましたね
Definitely on the way.
12 Days to Deadline
This is Musashino Animation.
Thank you for calling back!
I called you about keyframes...
Next time on Shirobako: "Exodus Christmas."
Exodus Christmas
（あおい）
はい 武蔵野アニメーションです
折り返し ありがとうございます
お電話 差し上げたのはですね
原画のご相談だったんですが…
次回
「ＳＨＩＲＯＢＡＫＯ(シロバコ)」